Emily Wallace - Price

<u>07722 466017</u>

emilywallace-price.co.uk

https://github.com/emmiejw

Core Skills

5 HTML5

B CSS3, Bootstrap 4, Materialize css

MySQL

Javascript with React.js framwork

PHP including Laravel PHP framework

Git source control

PHP myadmin

Python Django

Deployment onto Digital Ocean with Laravel Forge

>_ Command line

Professional Summary

- o I am a highly motivated and independent individual with an enthusiastic work ethic and attitude
- A level headed and rational approach to problem solving combined with a passion for innovative and fresh ideas that has led to a portfolio of impressive websites and applications.
- o All websites have been built with full stack web development and deployed onto configured servers.
- o Determined to find a solution to a challenge but I'm also not afraid to ask for guidance too.
- Very driven to produce functional and aesthetically pleasing sites that meet the needs of the client (making use of their site
 effortless and efficient)
- In every project I use at least one new piece of technology or more to advance my skills in a practical real life project.

Work History

Web Developer for Workplace Drugs & Alcohol Testing

March 2019 - ongoing support

I was approached by the CEO of WDAT in March of this year to create and design a website for her new business. We discussed her requirements for the website and the company forms she needed for the testing. I wanted to learn more about her business so I could tailor make the website to be unique from other drug and alcohol testing companies so WDAT would stand out. **Every step of the way I consulted with my client to make sure she was happy with the designs I then went into creating the site.**

I was enthused with this project because it was the first project where I didn't have to do any backend development and purely work on the front end. I built the site with Laravel and instead of Bootscrap 4 I used a different responsive front-end framework called Materialize css. I enjoyed implementing Parallex to images on the site, so as the user scrolls down the page the images move at a different speed. When the website content was added I used vanilla Javascript to expand for further text information and then was inspired to add other additional design functionalities.

Once my client was happy with the finished product I set up the domain name and **deployed onto a VPS server via Laravel Forge**. From here I was able to install SSL certificates. **The forms were created with HTML5 and bootstrap grid layout, making it easier to focus on each individual section**.

www.workplacedat.co.uk

Web Developer for Stepping Stones Preschool

Sept 2018 - ongoing support

I'm one of the Parent Governors at my sons' pre-school and during a meeting I offered to build them a website. The Manager and I had frequent meet up's to discuss the content and the information that was required. I initially thought the website would be a static website but due to policies, the Manager wanted to have complete control of the content. I created a admin area for the Manager to log on and use the CRUD functionality to keep the site current and up to date. To extend my skills I asked the Manager if she would like a testimonial page for parents to leave comments about the pre-school. She really liked the idea but wanted to be able to authorise the posts before they appear on the site. I was able to create this functionality within the Admin panel and I also set up Laravel Notifications so she would receive an email every time a notification was submitted.

www.steppingstones-hardley.co.uk

Web Developer for Hypo Hounds

March 2018 - ongoing support

A good friend of mine is the CEO of a charity called Hypo Hounds, who train pet dogs to alert their type 1 diabetic owners to impending dangerous blood glucose level changes, which these dogs can detect from a minute odour change in the owners scent. I knew the CEO at the time had to manually every 3 months, go through clients' individual blood glucose diary and the alert diary of the dog, which was very time consuming.

I approached her and offered to create a site for clients to log in and record both their blood glucose levels and the dogs' alert all in one place and can be completed there and then making the activity more efficient. Then every 3 months the client could email a report to the CEO. Upon discussion we decided to add a admin panel so she and the trainers could log into the site and view client records as and when they needed meaning they could provide support to clients a lot quicker and wouldn't need to chase clients when the reports were due.

This was my first live project that was going to be used in the real world and my focus was to make it user friendly and quick to use. Building the site was one thing but I had to learn about and how to deploy to a server and the relevant SSL certificates, setting up domains and namespaces for the server. I produced user guides for the clients on how to register an account and use the diary system. For the more visual people I created youtube videos as a guide. I was very pleased with my first website and it felt exhilarating to see my work online and even more so when the site became live to the clients. I've continued to provide support as and when any clients need support.

www.yourpartnershipdiary.co.uk

Administrator, Solent NHS Community Services

2010 to 2013

During this time I developed a reporting system of my own back for Senior Management at Associate Director Level, Daily
Status Report . This was a spreadsheet, which enabled me to calculate each community nursing teams' capacity each day to take on new patients on top of their routine caseload. This was forecasted by allocating 1 unit to 15 minutes of the staffing working day, e.g. a staff member working 7.5 hrs had a score of 30 units. This would then be done for each patient and how long the visit would take. The team would then be able to work out what capacity they had to take on additional patients. Based on this system to teams would text message or call me every morning giving me an alert of green for good capacity, amber for little capacity and red for no capacity and black if the team needed assistance from another team. From this information I could formulate a Daily Status Alert to senior Management and hospital discharge to see the current state of community nursing. I believe this was the start of journey into programming.

I also worked with the Patient Systems team to design and set up the first online patient system to be used in the community. Once the system was tailored to the services needs I attended a train the trainer course so I could roll out the training to the community nurses. This was quite a challenge with the majority being 'old school' nurses who preferred paperwork and didn't know how to use notebooks. Once this system was in place for some time I was then able to pull information of what activities were completed to **meet targets and qualify the service with more funding**, which was rewarding being able to justify how hard the teams work.

Health Care Assistant within District Nursing

2006 to 2010

In this role I worked as a health care assistant in a district nursing team. I predominantly worked with leg ulcer care and person care for palliative patients. I found this a very rewarding job and when the teams were provided **Blackberry mobiles I helped** with training to use them and also worked with the service Manager to create a wound photo declaration/assessment form. This was so staff could take photos of wounds and monitor the changes visually. This became very important when pressure ulcers needed to be reported to the Risk Management to eliminate or address safe guarding issues.

Volunteer and Speaker for Medical Detection Dogs

2010 to 2017

In 2011 due to the loss of my hypo awareness (where people with type 1 diabetes, are frequently unable to notice when they have low blood glucose). Medical Detection Dogs are a charity that train canines to alert their owner to an impending hypo from a change in the owners body scent, which changes as the blood glucose levels begin to rise or fall. This partnership was life changing for me so I wanted to help raise awareness and much needed funds for the charity.

I would provide support on event stands to support the team. I advertised locally to the groups that invited speakers to their meetings and I would talk passionately about the charity as well as my personal situation and how having my Medical Alert Dog changed my life.

Education

Education Establishment	Date	Subject	Grade
Lynda.com	August 2017	Programming Foundations	Completed
Lynda.com	August 2017	Python	Completed
Udemy	January 2017	The Complete 2019 Fullstack Web Developer Course	Completed
Udemy	April 2018	CSS3 responsive websites	Completed
Udemy	August 2018	PHP Laravel	Completed
Udemy	August 2018	Bootstrap 4	Completed
Udemy	Sept 2018	Laravel Chat App	Completed
Udemy	February 2019	Django Python Framework	Completed
Udemy		React.js Bootcamp	In progress
Udemy		Mastering React & Redux	In progress
Udemy		Modern React with Redux	In progress

Apprenticeship in Business and Administration Advanced Diploma.

NVQ 3 in Business and administration	Key skills	Workplace Development
 Contribute to running a project Design and produce documents in a business environment Plan and organise meetings Develop a Presentation Deliver a Presentation Analysis and Report Data Manage own performance and in a business environment Evaluate and improve own performance in a business environment Work in a business environment Communication in a business environment Work with others in a business environment Contribute to decision making in a business environment 	• Maths • English	 Principles of personal responsibility and how to develop and evaluate own performance at work Principles of working with and supervising other in a business environment Principles of managing and information and producing documents in a business environment Principles of providing and maintaining administrative services Principles of project management

Personal Statement

I am a calm problem solver who is used to challenges. I embrace new technologies, which has had a huge positive impact on my personal life. The last year I have been very privileged to now have access to medical technology, which has been life changing and I'm fascinated about the machine learning algorithms behind my intuitive medical device.

I've recently started getting involved in the web development meet up scene. I have given a talk to the Soton Women in Web group about diabetes technology, which I am very passionate about. Attending the group has been a real confidence boost in my abilities in preparation of applying for my first job in the industry. I am very proud to have achieved what I have in web development so far along side bringing up my now four year old son.

I am an enthusiastic learner who believes that even though it can take time to achieve a goal, the journey is an invaluable experience in understanding and discovering new technologies and styles. I know there is so much more to learn and what was once a daunting prospect I'm now eager to learn more a diversify my skills and knowledge.